Ok, for our next point now, we need to decide about the hair style, whatever the customer has decided how he would like his hair to go.
So, we're going to say for instance that this customer wants a parting.
Now, a parting should never begin higher that where the hairline begins on the hair piece.
So, you can see the hair through here, this is where we want to begin the parting.
If we began the parting here, then what would happen is when we get the hair piece back, we are going to have hair going over skin.
And unfortunately, even though these hair pieces are good, they're not so good that it doesn't actually show the hair going over the skin, it tends to give the hair piece away.
So, my suggestion for that is always to have the parting to begin wherever the hairline begins.
So, that would be at this point.
So, the customer wants a parting, so what I'm going to do is put a dotted line here and all the way back to about just the tip of the crown.
So with the customer having a parting, he obviously is not going have the hair going straight forward or going back.
So we still need to give some indication to our wig maker on what kind of style the customer is going to have.
So, what I'm going to do now is actually put the indication of the flow of the hair, so we want the hair to go around like this.
Now the reason I'm putting this slight curve into this is that any good wig maker will actually out each individual hair into the hair piece so it gradually starts to go back.
Same with this point of parting.
We don't want the hair being put into the base of the piece pointing this way, what we want is for the hair to be slightly pointed this way in the hair piece.
When the customer has a parting, the hair is going to flow backwards, and not forwards pushing itself onto the face.
A real head of hair tends to act differently than a hair piece, so you really do have to give the hair piece direction, which way to go.
So as I say, giving the hair direction like so.
So the hair piece is going to sweep around like this, the hair will come over the forehead and sweep around.